Kotschnig, Walter Maria; Papers ger053
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1927-1984; 2; 1402 folders
  - Correspondence with individuals connected with the International Student Service (I.S.S.), the Work Camps for America of the I.S.S., the European Student Relief Fund, the World Student Service and the World Student Service Fund, 1932-1971; 1936-1943; 2.1; 142 folders
    - MacCracken, Henry Noble, 1938; 1 item (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Mackie, Robert C. (World's Student Christian Association), 1940-1944; 64 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Mantoux, Etienne, 1942; 7 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Maufe, Gareth, 1933-1939; 14 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - McNary, Jean, 1939-1940; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - McNees, Rebecca, 1942; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Melby, Everett K., 1940-1942; 12 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Miller, Francis P., 1935; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Mook, Jane Day (Parker), 1937-1943; 10 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Moriarta, Hannah (Committee for Refugee Education, Inc), 1941-1942; 8 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Morley, Louise, 1940-1942; 38 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Morton, Helen, 1937-1942; 11 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Murray, Irene (United States Student Assembly), 1943; 4 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Murray, Sybil, 1940; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Neilson, William Allan (Smith College), 1936-1943; 28 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Neilson, Elisabeth, 1948-1952; 11 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Nelson, Claud, 1941; 9 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - New York Foundation (William F. Fuerst), 1939; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold (European Student Service Fund), 1940; 8 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Niebuhr, Muriel, 1940-1941; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Northwood, Arthur Jr. (National Student Federation), 1936; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Owen, Monica, 1942-1943; 6 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - Peirce, Robert, 1942; 1 item (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 92)
    - Pickett, Clarence E. (American Friends Service Committee), 1938-1943; 14 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 93)
    - Pobers (Pobereszki), Michel, 1940-1953; 54 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
    - Pobers, Tatiana, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
    - Poulson, Harper W., 1939-1940; 39 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 95)
    - Pratt, Eliot D., 1936-1949; 1952; 44 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 96)
    - Pratt, Trude W., 1937-1944; 80 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 97)
    - Robertson, Elizabeth (The National Student Federation of the United States of America), 1942-1943; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 98)
    - Robinson, Leland Rex (American Committee for Christian Refugees, Inc), 1939-1946; 20 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 99)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation (Raymond Fosdick, Sydnor H. Walker, Tracy B. Kittredge), 1939-1941; 20 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 100)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1942; 1949-1952; 1 signed; 11 additional items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 101)
    - Rosenwald, William (Rosenwald Family Association), 1940-1941; 10 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 102)
    - Ross, Irwin (Threshold; New Threshold), 1940-1943; 28 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 103)
    - Rowland, Wilmina (Billie; World Student Service Fund), 1940-1941; 11 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 104)
    - Rowland, Wilmina, 1942; 60 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 105)
    - Rowland, Wilmina, 1943; 72 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 106)
    - Rowland, Wilmina, 1944; 7 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 107)
    - Schaeffer, Marlies, 1939; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 108)
    - Schmoker, J. Benjamin, 1942-1943; 4 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 109)
    - Schneebeli, Max H., 1934-1952; 27 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 110)
    - Schnitzer, Ewald, 1943; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 111)
    - Schrager, Victoria, 1940-1941; 21 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 112)
    - Schweinburg, Maria J., 1941; 1 item (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 113)
    - Schwieso, Charles (Chuck) Jr., 1937-1939; 5 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 114)
    - Shankland, Katharine (Kay), 1942; 5 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 115)
    - Shapiro, Clara, 1940-1944; 8 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 116)
    - Shroyer, Ann, 1940; 6 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 117)
    - Shuster, George N., 1942; 1949; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 118)
    - Sommerich, Jane, 1939; 6 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 119)
    - Spivack, Robert G., 1937; 25 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 120)
    - Spivack, Robert G., 1938; 37 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 121)
    - Spivack, Robert G., 1939; 52 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 122)
    - Spivack, Robert G. (Commission to Study the Organization of Peace), 1940; 32 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 123)
    - Squire, Frank D, 1939-1941; 4 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 124)
    - Strayer, Maude-Louise, 1940-1941; 11 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 125)
    - Stuerm, Ruža Lukavská (American Friends of Czecho-Slovakia; Masaryk Institute), 1942-1943; 24 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 126)
    - Stuerm, Francis H., Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 126)
    - Tambussi, Ella, 1940; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 127)
    - Thomas, Jean, 1937-1946; 6 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 128)
    - Thomas, Wilbur, 1936; 1940; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 129)
    - Tucker, Luther (National Council of Student Christian Associations), 1937-1943; 9 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 130)
    - United Student Peace Committee, 1940; 1 item (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 131)
    - Van Dusen, Henry P. (Far Eastern Student Emergency Fund), 1937-1943; 8 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 132)
    - Waine, Edith, 1940; 4 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 133)
    - Warburg, Ingrid, 1939-1941; 21 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 134)
    - Wieting, C. Maurice, 1942-1943; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 135)
    - Wiggin, Anne (The American Committee for Christian Refugees), 1936-1942; 58 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 136)
    - Wiggin, Anne, 1943; 53 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 137)
    - Wiggin, Anne, 1944-1951; 17 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 138)
    - Wolfers, Arnold, 1937-1950; 54 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 139)
    - Woodall, Bertha, 1938; 2 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 140)
    - Yard, Molly (Far Eastern Student Service Fund), 1938-1942; 17 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 141)
    - Yarmolinsky, Adam (Student League of America), 1941-1942; 5 items (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 142)
  - General correspondence, individuals, organizations, 1932-1975; 1936-1943; 2.2; 647 folders
    This series contains correspondence (circa 4500 items) with family members, correspondence dealing with the Kotschnig family's immigration and naturalization process, employment, correspondence with colleagues, universities and organizations concerning general educational issues and educational reconstruction in post-war Germany, as well as correspondence concerning Kotschnig's publications. Noteworthy among the correspondents in this series are: Werner Bohnstedt, William G. Carr (Educational Policies Commission), Edna V. Cowell (World Federation of Education Associations), Betty Drury and Stephen Duggan (Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars), Rudolf Heberle, Henry W. Holmes, I. L. Kandel and Paul Monroe (World Federation of Education Associations; co-editors with Kotschnig of World Education), Grayson Kefauver (Liason Committee for International Education), Edward R. Murrow, James W. Parkes, Charles E. Payne, Reinhold Schairer (U.S. Committee on Educational Reconstruction), James T. Shotwell (Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), Ann C. Stewart, Stuart M. Stoke, John W. Studebaker, Frances A. Thomas (Commission to Study the Organization of Peace), Robert Ulich, Seth Wakeman, Harold Weston (Food for Freedom, Inc.), Howard E. Wilson, and George F. Zook (American Council on Education).
  - Correspondence with or concerning family members, 1939-1975; 2.3; 6 folders
    - Kotschnig, Christopher (son), 1942-1945; 14 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    - Kotschnig, Elined (wife), 1939; 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
    - Kotschnig, Enid (daughter), 1939-1941; 1975; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
    - Kotschnig, Ignaz (father), 1942; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
    - Kotschnig, Therese (mother), 1939-1941; 32 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
    - Priest, John Kotschnig (son), 1939; 1946-1970; 11 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - General correspondence, individuals, organizations, 1932-1975; 2.4
    - Adamic, Louis, 1942; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    - Adams, G. W., 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    - Adams, Walter, 1937-1943; 20 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
    - Adler, (Frederick Charles), 1938-1942; 1951; 14 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Adler, Hannah, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
    - Adult Education (Morse H. Cartwright), 1940; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - Alfred, Helen, 1942; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Altschul, Frank, 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Amann, Paul, 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - American Association of University Professions.Bulletin (Ralph L. Dewey), 1938; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - American Committee for Christian German Refugees, 1937-1939; 7 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - American Friends of German Freedom (Anna Caples), 1941; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1940-1943; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - The American Russian Institute (Harriett Moore), 1937-1942; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - American Sociological Review (Joseph K. Folsom), 1938; 1943; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - The American Teacher (George T. Guernsey), 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
    - American Youth Commission of the American Council on Education (Winthrop M. Southworth, Jr), 1940; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Anker, Charlotte, 1943; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - Armstrong, Mrs. Sinclair Howard, 1941; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - Arndt, C. O. (U.S. Office of Education), 1943; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Arrowsmith, Mary Noel, 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
    - The Aryan Path, 1937-1938; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
    - Atkinson, Carola, 1942; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1939; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    - Aufricht, Hans (Commission to Study the Organization of Peace), 1943; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    - Austrian Action, Inc. / Free Austrian Movement (Gregor Sebba, Gertrud Redlich), 1941; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
    - The Austrian National Committee, 1942; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
    - Austro-American Committee (Joe Maier), 1942; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
    - Austro American Tribune. Anti-Nazi Monthly, 1944; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
    - Baerwald, Paul, 1939-1941; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
    - Bagley, William C. (School and Society), 1940-1942; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
    - Bailey, David Algar, 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
    - Bailey, Robeson, 1942-1957; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
    - Baily, Harold James, 1942; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
    - Baker, Florence M., 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
    - Baker, Lucille, 1942; 1952; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
    - Baker, Mary D., 1937-1941; 19 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
    - Bakkum, Glenn A., 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
    - Balduf, Emery, 1940; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
    - Balling, Franz X.C., 1940-1941; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
    - Ballou, Richard Boyd, 1939-1951; 17 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Ballou, Elizabeth, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
    - Basch, Claire S., 1942; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
    - Basedow, Frederic, 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
    - Bassett, Jeanne, 1941; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
    - Bauer, Franz, 1939-1942; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    - Beck, F., 1932; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
    - Behrendt, Richard, 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
    - Belaunde, Victor Andres, 1940; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
    - Belches, Katharine, 1938-1941; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
    - Belgian Information Center, 1942; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
    - Bentwich, Norman (Council for German Jewry), 1937-1941; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
    - Berggren, Kerstin, 1940-1941; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
    - Bergstraesser, Arnold, 1937-1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
    - Berlowitz, Kurt B., 1936; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
    - Bigelow, Karl, 1939; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
    - Bingham, Alfred (Common Sense), 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
    - Biographical Dictionary of Leaders in Education, 1939; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
    - Blagden, Ralph M. (St. Louis Star-Times), 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
    - Blanchard, Leslie, 1939-1943; 11 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
    - Bloch, Naomi, 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
    - Boas, A., 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
    - Bohnstedt, Werner, 1935-1957; 44 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
    - Bomberger, Marjorie, 1939; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
    - Bonnet, Henri (International Institute of Intellectual Cooperation), 1934-1940; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
    - Borgese, Giuseppi Antonio, 1937; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
    - Bosshardt, Hans, 1939; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
    - The Boston Committee for Christian German Refugees, 1939-1941; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
    - Boston University, 1938-1939; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
    - Bowman, Isaiah, 1945; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
    - Bradley, Philip, 1937; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
    - Braisted, Paul J. (The Edward W. Hazen Foundation, Inc), 1942-1944; 16 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
    - Braunstein, Baruch, 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
    - Brinn, Lawrence E., 1937; 1939; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
    - Brinton, Howard, 1943; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - Brinton, Anna, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
    - British Information Services / British Library of Information (NY), 1942-1943; 16 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
    - Brooks, Kenneth G., 1942; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
    - Brooks, Murray, 1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
    - Brown, Esther Lucile, 1937-1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
    - Brown, Francis J. (The Annals), 1939; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
    - Brown, W. Sterry, 1942-1943; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
    - Browne, Roland A. (Dictionary of Education), 1941; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
    - Brownell, W. A., 1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
    - Brozek, J., 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
    - Bryant, Louise G., 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
    - Bryson, Gladys, 1939-1940; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
    - Buerki, Robin C., 1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
    - Buhler, Charlotte, 1945; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 92)
    - Bush, Merrill E., 1940-1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 93)
    - Butts, Marie, 1937-1944; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
    - Cabot, Charles C., 1940-1941; 7 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 95)
    - Cagle, E. M., 1942; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 96)
    - Caldwell, Otis W., 1938; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 97)
    - Campbell, Fay, 1939; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 98)
    - Cantril, Hadley, 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 99)
    - Carlson, Janet, 1940; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 100)
    - Carman, Harry J., 1944-1951; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 101)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Henry S. Haskell, Amy Heminway Jones, Malcolm W. Davis), 1939-1943; 32 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 102)
    - Carr, William G. (The Educational Policies Commission), 1937-1944; 21 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 103)
    - Carr-Saunders, A. M., 1936; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 104)
    - Carswell, Marion, 1943; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 105)
    - Carter, Phyllis, 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 106)
    - Cartwright, Morse A. (American Association for Adult Education;Journal of Adult Education), 1942; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 107)
    - Cary, Mary G., 1940; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 108)
    - Cavert, Samuel McCrea, 1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 109)
    - Chaddon, Mary Helen, 1937-1938; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 110)
    - Chalmers, A. Burns, 1939-1941; 7 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 111)
    - Chambers, M. M. (American Youth Commission), 1939; 10 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 112)
    - Cheek, Mary Ashby, 1938-1949; 13 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 113)
    - Cheney, Winifred, 1937; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 114)
    - Cherrington, Ben M., 1938-1944; 15 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 115)
    - Childhood Education, 1940; 1944; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 116)
    - Churchill, Frank Spooner, 1943; 10 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 117)
    - Clapp, Grace L., 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 118)
    - Clark, Edward T. ("The International Petition"), 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 119)
    - Clark, Elizabeth Pearson (Betty), 1940-1943; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 120)
    - Clark, William R., 1939; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 121)
    - Clason, Charles, 1943; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 122)
    - Clayton, Mara D., 1944; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 123)
    - Clifton, L. L., 1943; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 124)
    - Cockrell, Ewing, 1943; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 125)
    - Cohen, Gustave, 1942; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 126)
    - Cohen, Joseph W., 1943; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 127)
    - Collinson, Noyes, 1940; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 128)
    - Colm, Gerhard, 1938; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 129)
    - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace (Beryl Harold Levy), 1940-1944; 1976; 19 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 130)
    - Common Ground (Margaret Anderson), 1942; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 131)
    - Conant, James B., 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 132)
    - Condon, Mrs. Edward U., 1940; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 133)
    - Cook, Melvin J., 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 134)
    - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1940; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 135)
    - Council for Democracy (A. R. Allen, Ernest Angell), 1942-1943; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 136)
    - Cowell, Edna V. (World Federation of Education Associations), 1938-1941; 41 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 137)
    - Coxe, W. W. (Journal of Educational Sociology), 1939-1942; 11 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 138)
    - Cramer, Frederick (Fritz) H., 1938-1941; 6 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 139)
    - Curry, Peggy, 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 140)
    - Curti, Merle, 1941; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 141)
    - Curtis, Janet, 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 142)
    - Czernin, Ferdinand (Austrian Action, Inc. Free Austrian Movement), 1941-1945; 10 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 143)
    - Danes, Rosemary, 1939; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 144)
    - Danner, James W., 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 145)
    - David, Paul T., 1938-1939; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 146)
    - Davies, Gwilym, 1943-1944; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 147)
    - Davies, Lord, 1941-1943; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 148)
    - Davis, Helen M., 1943; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 149)
    - Davis, Herbert, 1944; 4 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 150)
    - de Angulo, Ximena, 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 151)
    - Deane, Sidney N., 1939-1942; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 152)
    - Del Vecchio, Georgio, 1937; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 153)
    - Demuth, F. (Notgemeinschaft deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland), 1935-1937; 9 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 154)
    - Derby, John B. (Office of War Information), 1945; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 155)
    - de Ropp, Stefan (Polish Information Center), 1942-1943; 8 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 156)
    - Dey, Mary Helena, 1937-1943; 10 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 157)
    - Douglass, Dorothy, 1941; 1 item (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 158)
    - Drayton, Betty B., 1942; 5 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 159)
    - Drebur, George K, 1941; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 160)
    - Drew, Helen L., 1939; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 161)
    - Drury, Betty (The Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars), 1937-1943; 29 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 162)
    - Dublin, Mary, 1938-1940; 7 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 163)
    - Duffield, Madeleine, 1940; 1943; 2 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 164)
    - Duffy, Alice, 1939-1940; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 165)
    - Duggan, Stephen (The Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars; Institute of International Education), 1937-1949; 24 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 166)
    - Dunlap, Flora, 1938; 3 items (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 167)